The clash begins.
Clash of the Titans is a adventure, fantasy, action
film directed by Louis Leterrier.
Born of a god but raised as a man, Perseus is helpless to save his
family from Hades, vengeful god of the underworld.
With nothing to lose, Perseus volunteers to lead a dangerous mission to defeat
Hades before he can seize power from Zeus and unleash hell on earth.
Battling unholy demons and fearsome beasts, Perseus and his warriors will only survive if
Perseus accepts his power as a god, defies fate and creates his own destiny.
Perseus, played by Sam Worthington.
Io, played by Gemma Arterton.
Draco, played by Mads Mikkelsen.
Andromeda, played by Alexa Davalos.
Calibos / Acrisius, played by Jason Flemyng.
Hades, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Clash of the Titans is a 2010 action fantasy film and remake of the 1981 film of the same name
produced by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (the rights to which had been acquired by Warner Bros.
in 1996 through its purchase of Turner).
The story is very loosely based on the Greek myth of Perseus.
An international co-production between the United States, United Kingdom, and Australia, the film is directed by Louis Leterrier from a screenplay by Travis
Beacham, Phil Hay, and Matt Manfredi, and stars Sam Worthington, Gemma Arterton, Mads Mikkelsen, Alexa Davalos, Ralph Fiennes, and Liam Neeson.
The film was originally set for standard release on March 26, 2010, but it was later
announced that the film would be converted to 3D and was released on April 2, 2010.
Clash of the Titans was a commercial success, grossing $493 million worldwide and becoming one of the highest-grossing films of 2010, but received mostly mixed-to-negative reviews from critics, with praise for
its epic scale, visual style, and the performances of Neeson, Fiennes, and Arterton, but criticism for Leterrier's direction, Worthington's performance, and the post-production 3D conversion.
The film's success led to a sequel, Wrath of the Titans, released in March 2012.
The film explores themes of hades, mythology, greek mythology, zeus, god.